we are starting today's episode as you
can see
by blowing up my base no not not that
bass we're just trying to dig this hole
now i severely underestimated just how
much tnt i would really need for this
so
i've used an entire shulker box full
that's 27 stacks of tnt
and i've only covered not even all of
these holes like that you can tell how
much i've really misinterpreted the
amount because these are all empty holes
only this little section here
is full of tnt
and i'm actually really worried that
this is going to cause a big explosion
on that's why i've made this safety wall
but
i mean let's just do what we're all here
for which is to blow oh wait i didn't
even fill that one up
oh no
okay the whole thing went up that's fine
that's fine
oh my goodness
it's still going
oh
boy
did it hurt my base
didn't make a protection big enough well
it worked i was kind of expecting
this to happen
but i wasn't expecting this to happen
i've lost all of this stuff was
predominantly junk anyway just you know
i just use this as a dumping ground
however
yeah i've lost some items there but
we're making progress oh no no they're
all here i may have to return
to mining out manually just because
this tnt thing isn't working out the way
i wanted it to and not only that just as
expensive and time-consuming also where
are the diamonds
seriously there should be at least a few
diamonds down here
so unlucky now i know from digging out
this side of the mansion
that it's going to take a lot more than
just one mining session however that
shouldn't put us off
i think we should probably start doing a
little bit of mining
and getting this
at least started so
i mean we just started the episode but
we've we've got to get some actual work
done on the base
it's it's pretty painful okay so let's
get this done
[Music]
little bit of bad news the next clip
that i recorded actually corrupted and i
managed to recover it but not the audio
so instead of the usual minecraft sounds
enjoy some nice elevator music and you
can pretend that there's minecraft
sounds going on so mining out this stuff
is not fun
what so
ever and as you can see i get through
quite a few pickaxes doing this stuff
but i've got to admit it's pretty
soul-destroying digging out this amount
so i'm gonna spread the load over a
couple of episodes of hermit craft just
so i just just so i could keep my
marbles really but i mainly stopped
because i saw that a few of the
resistance members etho and impulse were
actually online and i had an idea
a pretty dangerous idea that involves
maths but i'm not gonna do the math you
see so we're gonna meet up with them
wait are we we're falling
let's go over to the mycelium resistance
base and summon our friends probably not
worth an emergency meeting as much as
i'd love to hit the emergency meeting
button
it's probably not worth it well
looky here
he just did the wiggle dancer friendship
so my idea and what i'm gonna ask the
other two
is
what we were doing with the sheep and
spreading the mycelium was technically
very smart like it used minecraft
mechanics and surprisingly to everyone's
shock
it worked check it out insane
but then i thought
we don't actually own that land so what
if we use the diamonds from the diamond
throne and basically just give it back
so i'm going to propose this idea and
we'll see where it leads us and we can
legally take over at least half the
shopping district i'm not willing to run
the numbers on this thing so let's go
into the mycelium headquarters
and we're here
so
let's see if etho and impulse will join
us in the real and that this is the real
base i mean i don't even know
legitimately i don't know how to prove
that i'm in the real base there's so
many copies of this thing that
it's so confusing even for us on the
server that when you're inside you're
like ah wait am i am i in the correct
place there's only a few giveaways now
so anyway let's message them
i don't know what to say just impulse
etho like meetings about things and
stuff how do there's there's hep people
online tango cub x they're all online
and i was just like what nothing about
mushrooms just you know minecraft and
stuff okay right now we need to wait for
them
the next clip also lost all its audio
including all of ethos and impulses
fortunately impulse has given me his
audio but it means it won't match up
technical problems it happens let's just
enjoy all right thank you guys for for
coming along i promise you this is the
real bass i know it is really confusing
but we are in the real one it is
confusing
they look exactly the same they do that
they are identical and it's kind of been
weirding me out but there is no this is
my chair though i can sense my chair
yeah
right and that chair over there in one
of the fake ones is missing so that's a
kind of a giveaway and also uh the vault
is intact so we're definitely in the
right i love how it's so complicated now
that we don't even know which base is
ours you know
so i i asked you to come here today
because i had an idea of what to do with
the diamonds hep are up to something i
don't know if you saw but they're
building like a lot offshore and i was
thinking like while they're doing their
thing why don't we make a move and use
the diamonds that we have in the vault
and kind of like
legally in
minecraft speak
purchase half the shopping district and
then we can turn it to mycelium and we
don't even have to worry because it's
it's right
the land belongs to us we can do
whatever we want with it
exactly and you know i'm i don't i'm not
saying we buy the whole thing just half
just half
yeah yeah they get the diamonds back
then they're happy we're happy yeah
exactly
it's a win-win right i'm also not quite
willing to do the the maths on this so
do we still not have a button for this
thing no oh dude this is our fault this
is wait wait wait the the fake vault
actually looks better than this one
dude legitimately the fake one looks way
better than this uh no one showed mumbo
this because he'll be really upset
right let's take all these diamonds
that's a lot of things
and i'm not willing because it's like a
10 by 10 space to purchase uh for one
diamond block right mm-hmm who's got the
door we gotta we gotta secure it again
yep better secure that we'll never get
through that
all right let's go to the the town hall
here
and give these diamonds back i mean to
be honest with you we kind of cheesed it
oh my goodness i found the chair oh
it's just sitting in here yeah wait this
is all they have left is one diamond
[Laughter]
oh they're so poor
they've got no funds we kind of cheesed
this off them in the first place so like
it's not diamonds i think we could you
know really keep for ourselves it
doesn't feel quite right we kind of
cheesed this off them uh however
i think we're totally within our rights
to give it to give it back so if you
take a couple uh stacks of diamond
blocks i mean we we're literally talking
about hours of mining that we're playing
with here like this is a massive amount
of diamonds this is so many yeah oh my
goodness so we're just getting it
no dude we don't i don't
we don't technically have to put it back
exactly how we found it right
were you thinking we send a message yeah
i think we do we literally sent a
message
oh i know what you're saying is it about
the principal i don't know if
i don't know if we can fit that in i'm
just thinking gotcha
we don't have that big of a chaos here i
was thinking it was just have to be lol
i don't know let's see if it fits
yeah it may have to be lol now that i
i'm trying to do this
i think
are we going to do lol because i don't
think even
got and got lol
got lol
i don't know
what do you think just i think we're
gonna have to go for long yeah i think
we're gonna have to that that old
chestnut right how do we how do we want
to do this what can we what can we do
with the rest of the diamonds because i
i still got a lot of diamonds did we
just write we could just write lol a lot
oh like on every wall
yeah just like in various different
sizes okay okay
like a mini lol
just to rub it in just in case it wasn't
clear yeah there's a lot of diamonds to
use up here
i got a there's a little lollow over
here i'm going to put another little
hole here
i
didn't think it would come to this
we literally have too many diamonds we
can't make enough lulls
i love this so much
what are you scared
yeah okay so yeah
i mean i don't think i've ever seen
anyone scaffold in survival with
diamond
that's really quite insane like we're
dealing with
this is so much better than a diamond
throne by the way this is this is
genuinely very funny this feels very
surreal this it genuinely feels like
we're in creative mode that's like how
many diamonds right now
you shouldn't see this man
how did we mine this many diamonds this
season
there's lulls everywhere i love it
everywhere you look alone
does this mean it's no longer about the
principle it's just for the lols
oh
did the message just become long
that's the message
i've still got more diamonds oh no
really yeah
oh no
boom that's it the last actually there's
one there's one single diamond i'll
pop it back there there you go there we
go i'm not prepared to do the maths on
how much land this actually buys but i
think everyone here can safely assume
that it covers the area that we're
claiming oh yeah
it's a lot but we're not gonna we're not
gonna do that we're only claiming our
half which i've actually drawn a little
map
uh for everyone to show in their videos
so that we we kind of know where which
side that we want and so i think we
ought to mark it off but the thing is we
genuinely don't have enough mycelium to
do this job so we might have to come
back to it when we've got enough
mycelium but we can we can at least
divide up the the shopping district okay
this is hilarious i can't get over this
that's a lot of lulls
for sure oh my goodness
all right mission success team we have
officially bought half of the shopping
district and we can legally turn it to
mycelium
this ended up being way
way crazier and more fun than i thought
it was gonna be i i genuinely thought we
would just put the throne back but this
is better so we've also added some signs
the diamond throne has been returned lol
just kidding we have used the diamonds
to legitimately purchase half of the
shopping district we will be covering it
up very soon now this whole thing works
on the assumption that any block of
green grass is basically free real
estate okay so obviously people already
own a lot of land and we can't just go
around buying people's existing shops
however we can assume that places like
this where there's nothing going on
that we can do whatever we want with so
that's kind of the logic so we won't be
changing anything like this and we won't
be changing any like really heavily
terrain stuff so it's it works on logic
basically it's it's logic so you see
this grass this is up for grabs
you see this terrain grass this is not
up for grabs unless of course it is
owned by one of the resistance members
in which case ren may want this change
to mycelium so it all works on logic but
remember no one's going to have any sort
of issue with this and of course if we
do mess up in any sort of way i don't
think it's going to be a problem it's
just a bit of grass at the end of the
day it is just a bit of grass so
what is the line that we need to draw so
i here's the picture that i drew
and the line basically encompasses most
of our shops on the resistance plus a
few others where possible but like i
said we don't actually have any mycelium
left
so that leads me to think we might need
to recover some of the mycelium that we
actually
sold
to hep
in the first place we're basically just
trading this stuff but i again i'm not
sure that this is finished so
they need to they need to get a move on
because i want in oh there has been some
progress in other news tango and impulse
saw me fail
miserably at the trick or treat game
and they very nicely restocked it for me
so that i could try again even though
it's no longer halloween all i wanna do
is win just once so we're gonna try this
one more time maybe two maybe three
maybe four maybe maybe six depends on
how we do
right books in
we know we know how to play this game
bread how do we make bread with this
stuff what's in this stuff
whoa okay okay okay so
we need oh
i think i know how this works so we need
to
so we need to make a crafting table
because we need to
why can't i place i don't know if
they've thought this through there's not
enough light do i have to place this
near the light
do i have to place this by the light oh
yeah i do
oh man okay i'm going to spam this get
as much
bone meal as possible
that's gonna be rough
this is gonna be a rough rough start
come on come on i cannot get enough
i cannot get enough phobia i've figured
it out i'm just running out of time
that's got to be enough
and then quickly again
the stress
and then we craft up the bread
and we put the bread in the middle
it's going
we
come on
we did it
on the first attempt okay that was
how much time did we have left that's
what i want to know
we had we had a good amount of time left
easy peasy
easy peasy look at that 30 seconds to
spare at least
there it goes
kablooey
i really really love that little mini
game it's so cool
and it really tests your minecraft
skills and knowledge you really have to
think about it massive thank you to
tango at impulse for putting that
together for me again just so that i
could try that was really nice of them
and we had 44 levels which is not
something you want to lose out on
whoa
someone's cleared me out of bookshelves
should probably check on the barge i
need to do some restocking
so on the personal fund level we're
doing pretty well
i even got 20 diamond ore but i don't
actually remember where i got this from
let's see what we get so 20 diamond door
we would expect to get 40 i think
i have no idea what was there before so
i think we did pretty well
so how are we doing on the diamond front
one two three four stacks of diamond
blocks plus nearly another full one and
then a little bit on the end man we are
doing well this is quite the box back at
the base i have been collecting up lots
and lots of resources all over again now
the reason for this is because i'm
stocking up for the next edition of the
barge treasure hunts and the prize pool
is always really quite insane and it
usually takes me several days to collect
everything that i want to include in
these so i'm getting started right now
the next stage of the barge box treasure
hunt i don't know what it's going to be
called it's going to be called like a
barge box versus quest because here it
is i'm going to like lay it out for
everyone and explain how this is gonna
work
so
the this is gonna be a 2v2 treasure hunt
okay and it's going to start here at the
bar this is where the barge is now
you get you get your two hermits here
this is two hermits there we go let's
let's give them faces there we go these
are our four hermits
now here's the thing they are gonna get
a different clue each
okay so this one might be a clue that
leads them
in this direction to another another
point in the hermitcraft map and these
guys their clue will lead somewhere else
so they're going to divide up at some
point and they need to solve the clue
and it's a race these two are racing
against each other and then once they
get here they're gonna get another clue
and it's gonna go there and these guys
are gonna get the same clue that leads
them here i really mess that up and then
you'll you'll do the same again so
they'll get another clue and remember
this is a race and then they both should
in theory if i plan this thing properly
they end up here at the same place
and this is where they battle it out for
whatever it's not against each other i
see here's the problem i can't give it
all away i've got so many cool ideas for
this but i can't give it away otherwise
it spoils the whole thing but my
goodness
this is going to be expensive i'm
thinking it's 200 diamonds each
each individual hermit will have to pay
200 diamonds to take part in my race
quest race or so i don't i don't know
what it's called
but anyway there will be a first place
prize and a second place price so you'll
still get some value even if you don't
win the overall thing but as we know the
barge box hunts have been particularly
good on value so this is what i'm
working on and of course the first thing
to do is to get the rewards together so
i have off camera been working on that
mainly and then i've got some really
cool ideas for the different stages of
this quest hunt i'm figuring this part
out for my next few episodes
meanwhile there's just a casual war
going on i'm more worried about my barge
box so that's the plan there now etho
actually sent me a message and he saw
that i was working on this now i've been
slowly chipping away at
mining all of this out over over the
course of a few days every now and again
i just come along if i'm just afk or
whatever i'm just i'm just working on
this
i'm not recording i'm just sort of
chipping away at it then he came up to
me and said actually there is a really
good way or effective way to mine out
that isn't tnt
and he said it's using respawn anchors
now
you can't always trust what etho says so
this this could be dangerous but i do
know that respawn anchors explode in the
overworld so i've got 25 they're pretty
expensive to make but if we dig down
i mean we don't have to dig down far to
try this out
but here's here's how it goes so he said
you get a stack of respawn anchors just
like this now they're they're blast
resistant then you put an anvil on the
top so that you don't die
and then you
just do this
and you don't take any oh that is not
effective at all
um okay it's it's not it's not terrible
i'd say probably i'd say it's probably
more expensive than tnt
it is a brand new way of doing this i've
got to say this is a very intriguing but
i'm not i'm not convinced that this is
better than tnt to be honest especially
as it costs quite a lot of glowstone
but i mean it's very clever
very ingenious
but look it does only blast around there
oh do i oh do i only need one glowstone
uh okay i've been wasting a lot of
glowstone so it definitely has a
slightly bigger blast radius than tnt
but honestly i don't think it's that
much so i think if i try this again all
i gotta do is put one in and then try
and yeah that's it you put one glowstone
in then you can try and reset your spawn
and then it explodes
i mean it's very interesting i've never
i don't think i've ever seen this done
before
but i'm not sure it's that all that
effective especially as respawn anchors
are so much more expensive to make than
tnt
he said you just whoa
oh you instantly oh no now why did i oh
oh
oh no
oh no fire
oh no there was a lot of fire there oh
no
no this has done a lot of damage
please please please please okay
oh we got some we got some netherrite
tools here
oh man
oh no it wasn't dead in the nether it
was the other way round okay so when he
said anvil very very important oh how
much have i lost
i think i've been really lucky
oh
geez okay armor okay i think that was oh
oh no i got my sword in my i got my
sword and my superman oh man
we got so lucky there i
doesn't near the right
burn i can't even try it to be honest
with you i don't even know if
netherright burns in fire i know it
doesn't burn in lava so
logically it wouldn't burn in the fire
but i'm too much of a chicken to
actually try that one
okay so i think respawn anchors might be
a bit of a dud i must admit it was it
was fun to try it out but honestly i
think i'm gonna have to return
to mining again was a good suggestion by
etho and he definitely wasn't wrong
about the anvil don't try it don't try
it with an anvil okay without an anvil
because uh
it's just instant instant death there's
there's just nothing about it and it
also makes you jump out your skin i i
genuinely spook myself there i think the
biggest casualty was my level lost
so unfortunately i think that is all we
have time for in today's episode
we did try out a bunch of mining here
some of which were successful a lot of
which
wasn't
and of course we went and gave back the
diamond throne which we originally
cheesed so we actually got some things
done i'm not gonna lie to you this
episode has been a bit of a nightmare i
had some major major issues with the
footage so uh unfortunately i have
managed to fix it but yeah this this i'm
glad to see the back of this episode
even if it is number 50. but anyway
thank you very much for watching i hope
you enjoyed this video i'm gonna keep on
collecting some resources for
yet another barge box mystery hunt
there's a lot to do here so i better i
better get cracking i mean look this is
hours of chopping down trees so i shall
see you in the next episode good bye
you